Register of the Poland. Ambasada (United States) Records, 1918-1956
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1919-1952
  - Polish-Czechoslovak Declaration, London, January 23, 1942 (Folder 9)
  - Press and publicity
    - General, 1940-1941 (Folder 10)
    - American press, 1937-1940 (Folder 11)
    - Foreign language newspapers in the U.S., list, January 1943 (Folder 12)
    - International press
      - 1928-1938 (Folder 13)
      - 1941 (Box 84., Folder 1)
    - Journalists, Walter Lippmann, Martha Hemingway, etc., 1943-1944 (Folder 2)
    - Polish language press in the U.S., Poland Fights, 1945 (Folder 3)
  - Propaganda, Anti-Polish, 1938-1939 (Folder 4)
  - Raczkiewicz, Wladyslaw, President, Death of (Folder 5)
  - Raczynski, Edward, Count - Visit to Washington, February-March 1942 (Folder 6)
  - Rauschning, H., Dr. (Folder 7)
  - Refugees, Polish
    - Bulgaria, Romania, 1945 (Folder 8)
    - India, Iran, Mexico, United States, 1941-1944 (Folder 9-10)
  - Reparations, War, 1945-1948 (Folder 11)
  - Repatriation, Eleanor Roosevelt on, 1947 (Folder 12)
  - Roerich Museum, 1933 (Folder 13)
  - Romania, 1942, 1948-1949 (Folder 14)
  - Serbo-Lusatians (Folder 15)
  - Sikorski, Wladyslaw, General
    - Death, July 4, 1943 (Folder 16)
    - Visit to Moscow, 1941-1942 (Folder 17)
    - Visits to the United States
      - General, 1941-1953 (Folder 18)
      - General, 1941-1943 (Box 85., Folder 1)
      - 1941 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1942 March-April (Folder 4)
      - 1942 December-1943 January (Folder 5-7)
      - 1942 December-1943 January (Box 86., Folder 1-2)
  - Silesia, Upper - Plebiscite, etc.
    - 1919-1921 (Folder 3-6)
    - 1921 (Folder 7)
    - 1921 (Box 87., Folder 1-6)
    - 1921 (Box 88., Folder 1-6)
    - 1921 (Box 89., Folder 1-2)
    - 1922 (Folder 3)
    - 1925 (Folder 4)
    - 1926-1929 (Folder 5)
    - 1931-1932 (Folder 6)
  - Spain, 1949-1950 (Folder 7)
  - Stanczyk, Jan, International Labor Conference, 1944 (Folder 8)
  - Stockholm, Polish archives in (Folder 9)
  - Super, Paul (Folder 10)
  - Taft, Robert A. (Folder 11)
  - Tarnowski, Adam, note to British government, February 18, 1945 and note from Wszelaki, March 15, 1949 (Folder 12)
  - Treaties (Box 90.)
    - Chronological file
      - 1923-1924 (Folder 1)
      - 1925 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1928-1929 (Folder 4)
      - 1929-1930 (Folder 5)
      - 1939-1945, a list (Folder 6)
    - Alphabetial file
      - US-Polish Treaty of Arbitration, 1921 (Folder 7)
      - US-Polish Treaty of Friendship, Commerce and Consular Rights, 1923-1929 (Folder 8-9)
      - US-Polish Treaty of Friendship, Commerce and Consular Rights, 1923-1929 (Box 91., Folder 1)
      - US-Polish Convention on Prohibition of Smuggling of Alcoholic Beverages, 1930 (Folder 2)
      - Various (Folder 3-7)
      - Various (Box 92., Folder 1-2)
  - Ukraine and Ukrainians
    - General, ca. 1919 (Folder 3-7)
    - General, ca. 1919 (Box 93., Folder 1-4)
    - Chronological file
      - 1920 (Folder 5)
      - 1921-1923 (Folder 6)
      - 1929-1930 (Folder 7)
      - 1932-1933 (Folder 8)
      - 1935-1936 (Box 94., Folder 1)
      - 1938 (Folder 2)
      - 1938-1943 (Folder 3)
      - 1939 (Folder 4-6)
      - 1940 (Folder 7)
      - 1941 (Box 95., Folder 1)
      - 1943 (Folder 2-3)
    - Alphabetical file
      - Emigration (Folder 4)
      - National organizations (OUN, UVO, ODRU) and activity, 1935-1937 (Folder 5-7)
      - Protest of American recognition of USSR, 1933 (Folder 8)
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR) (Box 96.)
    - Chronological file
      - 1919-1922 (Folder 1-5)
      - 1920-1924 (Folder 6)
      - 1923-1924 (Folder 7)
      - 1930-1932 (Box 97., Folder 1)
      - 1948-1949 (Folder 2)
    - Alphabetical file
      - Deportees, Polish, in, Professor J. Parnas (Folder 3)
      - Foreign policy, surveys by V. Chernov, 1943-1945 (Folder 4-6)
      - Peace negotiations with, 1920-1921 (Folder 7)
      - Relations with
        - General (Folder 8)
        - 1939-1943 (Folder 9)
        - 1941-1942 (Folder 10)
        - 1942-1943 (Folder 11)
        - 1943-1944 (Box 98., Folder 1-2)
        - 1944 (Folder 3-4)
  - United Nations
    - Dumbarton Oaks Conference, San Francisco Conference, etc., 1944-1945 (Folder 5-7)
    - Dumbarton Oaks Conference, San Francisco Conference, etc., 1944-45 (Box 99., Folder 1)
    - East European national representatives, Protest to, 1948 (Folder 2)
    - Monetary and Financial Conference, Bretton Woods, New Hampshire, July 1-22, 1944 (Folder 3)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA)
    - General
      - 1943 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1943, 1945 (Folder 6)
      - 1944 (Folder 7-8)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 100., Folder 1-5)
    - Agreement
      - Draft, 1942 (Folder 6)
      - Final, November 12, 1943 (Folder 7)
    - Poland, Mission to, 1944-1945 (Folder 8)
  - United States
    - Armament, 1937-1938 (Folder 9)
    - Armament of merchant ships, 1941 (Folder 10)
    - Attitude toward Poland, 1943 (Folder 11)
    - Citizens of, 1932 (Folder 12)
    - Commercial agreements with Poland
      - 1934 (Folder 13)
      - 1937-1940 (Box 101., Folder 1-5)
    - Elections, 1938 (Folder 6)
    - Foreign relations
      - 1933 (Folder 7)
      - 1934 (Folder 8)
      - 1937-1940 (Box 102., Folder 1-4)
      - 1935 (Folder 5-7)
      - 1936 (Folder 8)
      - 1936-1937. Includes some material dating from 1924 (Box 103., Folder 1)
      - 1937 (Folder 2)
      - 1940 (Folder 3)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 4)
    - Government
      - 1935 (Folder 5)
      - 1939 (Folder 6)
    - Military assistance to Europe, 1949 (Folder 7)
    - Neutrality Act, 1939 (Folder 8)
    - Politics
      - Democratic National Convention, Chicago, 1940 (Folder 9)
      - Emigration, Role of, 1941 (Folder 10)
      - Republican Party, 1952 campaign (Folder 11)
    - Slav Congress, 1938 (Folder 12)
  - Vatican (Folder 13)
  - Viereck, George Sylvester (Folder 14)
  - Voice of America, Polish comments on (Folder 15)
  - Washington Conference of Arms Limitation, 1921 (Folder 16)
  - Washington Conference of Arms Limitation, 1921 (Box 104., Folder 1-3.)
  - World Economic Conference, 1933 (Folder 4)
  - World Union of Poles abroad, 1939 (Folder 5)
  - World War, 1939-1945
    - Arrests, Political (Folder 6)
    - Contraband (Folder 7)
    - French campaign, 1940, First Polish Division (Folder 8)
    - Poland
      - General
        - 1944 (Folder 9)
        - 1944-1945 (Folder 10)
      - Occupation
        - German
          - General
            - 1939-1940 (Folder 11)
            - 1939-1940 (Box 105., Folder 1-3.)
            - 1941 (Folder 4-7)
            - 1941 (Box 106., Folder 1-3.)
          - Culture and education, Destruction of, 1941 (Folder 4)
          - Liberation of prisoners, 1945 (Folder 5)
          - Professors of Jagiellonian University, Cracow, arrested, 1940 (Folder 6)
          - War crimes, 1942-1944 (Folder 7-8)
        - German and Soviet
          - 1943 (Folder 9)
          - 1944 (Folder 10)
          - 1944 (Box 107., Folder 1)
      - Transfer of populations (Folder 2)
      - Warsaw Uprising, 1944 (Folder 3)
    - War aims, Allied, 1940-1942 (Folder 4)
    - War work
      - General
        - 1939 (Folder 5)
        - 1942-1943 (Lend-lease, Red Cross, etc.) (Folder 6-7)
        - 1942-1945 (Lend-lease, Red Cross, etc.) (Box 108., Folder 1-6)
        - 1942-1943 (Lend-lease, Red Cross, etc.) (Box 109., Folder 1)
      - Polish deportees in the USSR
        - 1941 (Folder 2-7)
        - 1942-1950 (Box 110., Folder 1)
      - Prisoners of war in the USSR, Polish, 1940-1942 (Folder 2)
  - Yalta Conference, 1945 (Folder 3)
  - Yugoslavia, 1941-1943 (Folder 4)
- MISCELLANY, 1920-1946
  - YugoslaviaCorrespondence (Box 110., Folder 4)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych, 1920 (Folder 5)
    - Stanczyk, Jan, 1946 (Folder 6)
  - Subject file
    - Conversations of Minister Beck with Ambassador Bullitt, 1937 November (Folder 7)
    - Entry visas, 1936 (Folder 8)
    - Legal investigations
      - 1936-1937 (Folder 9)
      - 1937-1939 (Folder 10)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych. Bulletin entitled "Polska a Zagranica"
      - 1937 (Folder 11)
      - 1938 (Folder 12)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 111., Folder 1)
    - Polish communist movement, 1935-1937 (Folder 2)
    - Public safety, 1933 (Folder 3)